<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>CTF - Tag - Qi Qin</title><link>https://leoq7.com/tags/CTF/</link><description>CTF - Tag - Qi Qin</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 16:55:28 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leoq7.com/tags/CTF/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TON CTF 2024 Writeup</title><link>https://leoq7.com/2024/09/TON-CTF-2024/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 16:55:28 +0800</pubDate><author>Qi Qin</author><guid>https://leoq7.com/2024/09/TON-CTF-2024/</guid><description>Preface The TON CTF 2024, sponsored by the TON Foundation and organized by Tonbit and TONX Studio, was an exciting competition that featured 8 challenges. The tasks were divided into three categories: 3 easy challenges worth 100 points, 3 medium challenges worth 200 points, and 2 difficult ones valued at 300 points.
What made this CTF unique was that all the challenges were written in Tact, a high-level language designed for the TON ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>2023 MetaTrust Web3 Security CTF Sui Challenges Writeup</title><link>https://leoq7.com/2023/09/MetaTrust-CTF-Sui/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 17:55:28 +0800</pubDate><author>Qi Qin</author><guid>https://leoq7.com/2023/09/MetaTrust-CTF-Sui/</guid><description>Preface Last week, I participated solo in the 2023 MetaTrust Web3 Security CTF. In addition to the traditional Solidity challenges, Mysten Labs and OtterSec provided four Sui Move challenges as a separate category. Fortunately, I managed to get two first bloods and two second bloods, placing me first in this specific track. Apart from these four challenges, there was also an intriguing challenge involving Move bytecode reverse engineering. Since I have previously written several related writeups, I won&amp;rsquo;t delve into it here.</description></item><item><title>PBCTF 2023 Move VM Writeup</title><link>https://leoq7.com/2023/02/PBCTF-Move-VM/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 17:55:28 +0800</pubDate><author>Qi Qin</author><guid>https://leoq7.com/2023/02/PBCTF-Move-VM/</guid><description>Preface This weekend, I participated in the pbctf 2023 and got the first blood for the reverse challenge Move VM. Here is a brief writeup for this challenge.
Challenge Info Challenge Info Attachment: message.mv Solves: 6 Score: 383 In this challenge, we are given a message.mv file, which is a serialized Move module. As this is a reverse challenge, we need to reverse the module, analyze the algorithm that checks the flag and finally calculate the flag.</description></item><item><title>CTF MOVEment with Aptos Dec 2022 Writeup</title><link>https://leoq7.com/2022/12/CTF-Movement-Aptos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 17:55:28 +0800</pubDate><author>Qi Qin</author><guid>https://leoq7.com/2022/12/CTF-Movement-Aptos/</guid><description>Preface It&amp;rsquo;s been half a year since I last wrote a blog. During that time, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot about Web3 security, including Solana and Aptos. Last weekend, I participated in the CTF MOVEment with Aptos Dec 2022 jointly organized by MoveBit, Aptos, ChainFlag and OtterSec, and scored two first-bloods and two second-bloods in the four challenges except the sanity-check, ranking first in the end. In this post, I will briefly introduce the solutions to the five challenges.</description></item></channel></rss>